we're going to
use the select method to gather only the
immediate family members names
from this hash into a new array
so we see this family hash on lines one
through five
and this hash has four key value pairs
each value is actually an array of
strings
so we know we want to invoke the select
method on this hash
and when calling the hash select method
each key value pair is going to be
passed to the block
the first block parameter k will
represent the key
and the second block parameter v will
represent the value
now the select method will return a new
hash
containing the key value pairs for which
the return value
of this block evaluates as true
so we need to do some type of comparison
here on line 8.
we know that we want to include only the
immediate family members
in this new hash so that would be only
the sisters and brothers
so in order to select the appropriate
key value pairs
we can simply compare the key to the
symbols sisters and brothers
these are going to be our key value
pairs related to immediate family
members
if the key is equal to the symbol
sisters
or brothers
then these are immediate family members
let's store the returned hash in a
variable
[Music]
and just output this new hash
so we see our new hash that has two key
value pairs
this is what we want however in our
final result we only want the names
which in this case
are the values
we can invoke the hash values method
to return an array of the values in that
hash
again let's run this code and output
that with p
okay and this is closer to what we want
we see all the names of the immediate
family members
but you can see that the array we have
right now is a two-dimensional array
we have two elements in this array the
array of the names of the sisters
and the array of the names of brothers
we want just a one-dimensional array
here
we can invoke the array flatten method
this will return a flat one dimensional
array
and let's store this new array
in a variable r and output that array
and there we have our final result
you